<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2023 anarcat <anarcat@debian.org> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.dweymouth.supersonic</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <name>Supersonic</name>
  <summary> A lightweight cross-platform desktop client for Subsonic music servers</summary>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <description>
    <p>
      A lightweight cross-platform desktop client for Subsonic music
      servers (Navidrome, Gonic, Airsonic, etc).
    </p>

    <p>
      Features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Fast, lightweight, native UI, with infinite scrolling</li>
      <li>High-quality gapless audio playback powered by MPV, with optional  audio exclusive mode</li>
      <li>ReplayGain support (depends on files being tagged on server)</li>
      <li>Scrobble plays to server, with configurable criteria</li>
      <li>Primary and alternate server hostnames, e.g. for internal and external URLs</li>
      <li>Browse by albums, artists, genres, playlists</li>
      <li>Album and playlist views with tracklist and cover image</li>
      <li>Artist view with biography, image, similar artists, and discography</li>
      <li>Create, play, and update playlists</li>
      <li>Configure visible tracklist columns</li>
      <li>Set/unset favorite and browse by favorite albums, artists, and songs</li>
      <li>View and edit play queue (add and remove tracks; reorder support  coming soon)</li>
      <li>Shuffle and repeat playback modes (partial; shuffle album,  playlist, artist radio, random songs)</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.dweymouth.supersonic.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dweymouth/supersonic</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/issues</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The options dialog</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/AlbumsView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/AlbumView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/ArtistView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/FavoriteSongsView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

 <releases>
  <release date="2023-04-22" version="0.1.0">
   <description>
     <p>
       Version 0.1.0 release of Supersonic!
     </p>

     <p>
       Added
     </p>

     <ul>
       <li>Add playback settings dropdown to choose output audio device</li>
       <li>Add file path column to tracklist view</li>
       <li>Add (optional) system tray menu and close to tray support</li>
       <li>Show disc number and disc count for multi-disc albums</li>
       <li>Add search bar to artist, genres, and playlists pages</li>
       <li>Add alternate (e.g. external) hostname to server connection config</li>
       <li>Add "..." button to album page with menu to add album to queue or playlist</li>
       <li>Add searchable "All Tracks" page, with button to play random tracks</li>
       <li>Add experimental support for setting custom application font</li>
     </ul>
     <p>
       Fixed
     </p>

     <ul>
       <li>Don't show update available prompt if the found version is the same as the running app version</li>
       <li>Update Mac build process to support OS versions back to High Sierra (thanks @whorfin!)</li>
       <li>Navigating back twice to an albums page with search result clears search state</li>
    </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
 </releases>

</component>
