<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2023 anarcat <anarcat@debian.org> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.dweymouth.supersonic</id>
  <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <name>Supersonic</name>
  <summary> A lightweight cross-platform desktop client for Subsonic music servers</summary>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
    <content_attribute id="social-audio">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <description>
    <p>
      A lightweight cross-platform desktop client for Subsonic music
      servers (Navidrome, Gonic, Airsonic, etc).
    </p>

    <p>
      Features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Fast, lightweight, native UI, with infinite scrolling</li>
      <li>Light and Dark themes, with optional auto theme switching</li>
      <li>High-quality gapless audio playback powered by MPV, with optional  audio exclusive mode</li>
      <li>ReplayGain support (depends on files being tagged on server)</li>
      <li>Scrobble plays to server, with configurable criteria</li>
      <li>Primary and alternate server hostnames, e.g. for internal and external URLs</li>
      <li>Browse by albums, artists, genres, playlists</li>
      <li>Album and playlist views with tracklist and cover image</li>
      <li>Artist view with biography, image, similar artists, and discography</li>
      <li>Create, play, and update playlists</li>
      <li>Configure visible tracklist columns</li>
      <li>Set/unset favorite and browse by favorite albums, artists, and songs</li>
      <li>View and edit play queue (add and remove tracks; reorder support  coming soon)</li>
      <li>Shuffle and repeat playback modes (partial; shuffle album,  playlist, artist radio, random songs)</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.dweymouth.supersonic.desktop</launchable>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dweymouth/supersonic</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/issues</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The options dialog</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/AlbumsView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/AlbumView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/ArtistView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.github.com/dweymouth/supersonic/main/res/screenshots/FavoriteSongsView.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

 <releases>
  <release date="2023-05-05" version="0.2.0">
   <description>
     <p>
       Version 0.2.0 release of Supersonic!
     </p>

     <p>
       Added
     </p>

     <ul>
       <li>Add rating column to tracklist with 5-star rating widget</li>
       <li>Add light theme, and optional auto-switching between dark and light</li>
       <li>Add grid view option to playlists page with playlist cover images</li>
       <li>Enable click-to-seek behavior in seek bar</li>
       <li>Add context menu to items in grid views (albums and playlists)</li>
       <li>Add Ctrl+W (Cmd+W on Mac) shortcut to close to tray if enabled</li>
       <li>Add tracklist context menu items to bulk set favorite and rating</li>
       <li>Add "meatball menu" actions to playlist page</li>
       <li>Add settings option to choose startup page</li>
       <li>Migrate to Fyne 2.3.4 (few performance and memory improvements)</li>
       <li>Track title in bottom panel links to track location on Now Playing page</li>
       <li>Clicking thumbnail in bottom panel shows full size cover</li>
       <li>Add volume adjustment options to system tray menu</li>
     </ul>

     <p>
       Fixed
     </p>

     <ul>
       <li>Fix crash when searching for albums on Airsonic servers</li>
       <li>Tracklist columns occasionally misaligned when shrinking window</li>
       <li>Disable hyperlinks for track artists that are not also album artists</li>
       <li>Fix crash when navigating to "Top Tracks" on artist page not yet fully loaded or invalid artist</li>
       <li>Don't pluralize "tracks" for albums and playlists with only one track</li>
     </ul>
   </description>
  </release>
 </releases>

</component>
